Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/yiwen-ding-ab133a217 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Full-Stack Development Node.js React

Yiwen Ding

GHC'23 | SDE Intern @ Expedia | MSCS @ UCLA 24' Los Angeles, California, United States

Summary

Hi, I am a graduate student at the University of California, Los Angeles, currently pursuing a Master of Science degree in Computer Science. Before, I graduated from the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor with a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science. I am familiar with C++, Python and have 3+ years of experience in object-oriented programming. I am passionate about learning and working in software engineering, web development and machine learning related topics.

In my spare time, I pay close attention to social problems and make efforts to tackle those challenges using advanced technology. I also enjoy pilates and yoga, and love to travel when I have long vacation.

I am currently looking for a 2024 NG SDE position to promote my professional growth. I'd love to stay connected, please feel free to reach out!

Experience

Expedia Group Software Engineer June 2023 - September 2023 (4 months) Seattle, Washington, United States

Language and Information Technology Research Group Research Assistant March 2021 - July 2022 (1 year 5 months) University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Advisor: Prof. Rada Mihalcea

- Led the project which combined NLP with causality inference to conduct the first up-to-date AI community-wise statistical comprehensive analysis from citation trends, co-authorship, and linguistic styles of papers
- Curated a dataset of 78K researchers' profile and their publications using APIs and BeautifulSoup, developed transformer-based prediction model in

Page 1 of 2

PyTorch and sklearn for citations and conducted ablation and correlation studies

 Obtained 3 main findings to support community changes in AI and submitted the paper to FAccT 2023 for review

University of Michigan Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program

Research Assistant

January 2021 - January 2022 (1 year 1 month)

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Advisor: Prof. Andrew Gronewold

- Collaborated with industrial sponsors to fulfill their requirement of incorporating weather forecast information to improve Honda traffic time prediction system
- Cleaned traffic data in Michigan for model input and replicated Yaguang's
 Diffusion Convolutional Recurrent Neural Network for traffic speed prediction
- Reached a relative mean absolute error of 8% and outperformed the baseline model without weather data by 20%

Education

University of California, Los Angeles

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science · (September 2022 - June 2024)

University of Michigan

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2018 - 2022)